This video shows how to set up multiple
locations for inventory and how to use
transfer orders to move items between
the locations. In the warehouse manager
role, click on reference data to find
the location
[Music]
setup. A few locations are already set
up. We can set up as many locations as
we need and enter information about them
on the location
card. If we use intransit locations, we
can specify it on the location card.
We'll need to set up an inventory
posting group for each location. It's a
good idea to review the existing
inventory posting group setup. Now, we
can start purchasing items for a
location by entering the location code
in the purchase
document. If we want to see where items
are, the item card shows availability in
each location. When we sell items, we
can choose the location where we ship
the items
from. We can simply specify which
location to ship the item from in the
item
card to help us provide quality service
to our customers. On the customer card,
we can specify a default location to
ship from for each
[Music]
customer. For example, we can choose a
location that ensures speedy delivery
because it's close to the customer.
[Music]
When we need to move items from one
location to another, we use transfer
orders to document where the items went.
Depending on our needs, we can ship and
receive the items in one go, line by
line, and even partially. If we move the
items all at once, we can just choose
the direct transfer check box on the
transfer order. Otherwise, we'll use the
intransit code to select an intransit
location to track items during the
transfer. To avoid selecting the
intransit code every time, we can set up
transfer routes where the location is
already chosen. We can also specify a
specific shipping agent for a transfer
route. Business Central can let us know
when we're selling an item that is out
of stock at a specific location.
[Music]
When we want to sell an item that's out
of stock in one location, we can check
availability in other
locations. We can also use various
reports to check item availability at
specific locations. We just need to
choose one. Thank you for watching this
video.